<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Heather's Coding Journey]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Becoming a fullstack developer]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://heatherpike.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-11T05:41:36.009Z</updated>
  <id>http://heatherpike.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Heather Pike]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[heatherlaurenpike@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://zespia.tw/hexo/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[It's Official]]></title>
    <link href="http://heatherpike.github.io/2015/01/10/It-s-Official/"/>
    <id>http://heatherpike.github.io/2015/01/10/It-s-Official/</id>
    <published>2015-01-11T01:10:15.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-11T01:27:50.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday was my last day working as a marketing manager. I have finally walked away from a decade-long career to start over fresh. It’s liberating and terrifying all at the same time. I’m officially changing careers!</p>
<p>I was good at marketing - will I be better at coding? We’ll find out soon… if anything, I hope to enjoy it more and gain an increased sense of fulfillment. Studying the fundamentals of javascript and jquery, html, css, node, and test-driven development over the last several weeks has been fun for me - I think that’s a good sign that I will like being a developer.</p>
<p>Class at Fullstack begins in less than 48 hours. I am still finishing up my pre-work, but I feel confident that the 120+ hours of studying I’ve invested over the last month have provided me with the foundation I need to hit the ground running. </p>
<p>My main pre-work project was to create a simple number guessing game to bring my javascript/jquery, html and css skills together. It’s nothing fancy, but it works! And it took a lot of work for this burgeoning developer. Check it out!</p>
<p><a href="http://heatherpike.github.io/guessing_game/" target="_blank" rel="external">Guessing Game</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Yesterday was my last day working as a marketing manager. I have finally walked away from a decade-long career to start over fresh. It’s ]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Feeling Ready for Fullstack]]></title>
    <link href="http://heatherpike.github.io/2015/01/04/Feeling-Ready-for-Fullstack/"/>
    <id>http://heatherpike.github.io/2015/01/04/Feeling-Ready-for-Fullstack/</id>
    <published>2015-01-04T23:45:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-05T00:00:28.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I can’t believe 2015 is already here! I spent most of my December plowing through the pre-work for Fullstack Academy. It was REALLY tough trying to learn a lot of the concepts on my own (hence, why I decided to attend a bootcamp instead of teach this stuff to myself), but I am really proud and amazed at how far I have come in just a few weeks. </p>
<p>Before applying to Fullstack, I had dabbled in web design and computer science here and there over the years but never went farther than the basics. My knowledge of JavaScript was limited to the Codecademy introductory course. Just last month, I went from having a mere curiosity about coding to feeling like I can actually solve problems and build some things.</p>
<p>I’m certainly no expert yet, but I already feel like I can figure a lot out on my own, even though it might take me hours of research and trial and error before I get it right. </p>
<p>The feeling of accomplishment I already have makes me that much more excited to start class at Fullstack on Jan. 12. I can only imagine how much more accelerated my learning process will become when I have the live support of my teachers and others who are eager to learn. If I could teach myself so much in just a month, then going full-time, in-person for 3 months will surely be transformational. </p>
<p>I can’t wait!</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I can’t believe 2015 is already here! I spent most of my December plowing through the pre-work for Fullstack Academy. It was REALLY tough]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="coding, learning" scheme="http://heatherpike.github.io/tags/coding-learning/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[New Year, New Career]]></title>
    <link href="http://heatherpike.github.io/2014/12/14/New-Year-New-Career/"/>
    <id>http://heatherpike.github.io/2014/12/14/New-Year-New-Career/</id>
    <published>2014-12-15T04:01:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2014-12-15T05:39:47.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello World! I am about to embark on a journey to change careers. I am becoming a software developer! My desire to become a developer boils down to my yearning to create things and use my brainpower to the fullest!  </p>
<p>I was always naturally gifted in math and problem solving as a child, but I was also talented with English and writing - being a girly girl with no techie disposition, I ended up going down the MARCOMM path - I have long regretted it because I think I would have excelled more in math or tech. I took a CS101 course and a web design course in college and I really enjoyed and excelled at both, but I can’t tell you why I never pursued those topics further - could have been senioritis, as I think I took those my last year of college and I was probably ready to just get out there into the real world. </p>
<p>Now, years later, I have built a career in digital and brand marketing and earned my MBA in 2008. It’s been an exciting career and I have learned a lot over the years, but I’ve always had this nagging feeling like I missed my calling. </p>
<p>I yearn to create things and put my critical thinking skills to use. My personality sits the fence between introversion and extroversion but I lean more toward the introverted side; my current career forces me to flex my extroverted side and go outside my comfort zone, which is good experience but has been exhausting! </p>
<p>For some reason I always thought I should push myself to develop those areas in which I was not strongest; however, a book I read through work a couple years ago, Strengths Finder, opened me up to the opposite perspective. This book encourages individuals to nurture their strengths rather than work on their weaknesses. After reading this book I have felt more and more like I am not in the right career because I know I would excel so much more if I were doing something that leveraged my natural problem solving and mathematical talents.</p>
<p>I have been thinking about going back to school to learn to code for a long time but didn’t think it would be feasible until I heard about the bootcamp option. About 5-6 years ago, before bootcamps like Fullstack Academy existed, I visited a university to find out what it would take to get a second bachelor’s in computer science. I was told it would take 3 years. That discouraged me, and at the time I was still pretty green in my marketing career and enjoying the early phases of it, so I decided to continue on that path at the time. However, the thought that I was meant for something else continued to linger in the back of my mind. </p>
<p>I work in the education industry, and someone in my current company posted a link to an article about a programming bootcamp a little over a year ago. My heart soared when I realized it was exactly what I needed! </p>
<p>I recently moved to NYC, just down the street from Fullstack, and I finally decided to make my time here count by enrolling in the January 2015 cohort. In preparation for bootcamp, I am spending the next 4 weeks flooding my brain with the basics of Javascript, git, node.js, and the like while trying to improve my command of the command line as I learn to navigate the terminal on my shiny new Macbook Air. </p>
<p>It’s a crazy time as I stuff my brain full of new knowledge while wrapping things up at my marketing job. I am so excited to start the immersive bootcamp experience on Jan. 12 and be on my way to becoming a pro dev! </p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Hello World! I am about to embark on a journey to change careers. I am becoming a software developer! My desire to become a developer boi]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
